# MOHAMMAD AHMER MALICK

# WEB DEVELOPER / WEB DESIGNER

https://www.mohammadahmermalick.com

# CONTACT

- +971 545153604 Till Feb-20-2023 +92 3494941593
- mohammadahmermalick@gmail.com
- Dubai, United Arab Emirates
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/ mohammad-ahmer-malick-1a6586175/

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Denovers**

Full Stack Web Developer Full Time December 2021 - December 2022

## **Phoenix Technologies**

Front End Developer Full Time May 2021 - November 2021

## **Bizz World Communications**

Web Developer Full Time January 2020 - January 2021

Junior Developer Internship August 2019 - November 2019

## **Freelancing**

Graphic Designer Part Time

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a Computer Scientist with more than three years of field experience as a Web Developer. Currently located in UAE till February-20-2023. I have developed analytical skills with expertise in handling teams along with other challenges.

I am Specialize in developing responsive, search engine optimized, speed optimized web applications and websites and have extensive experience in frontend and can handle backend on multiple programming languages, also capable of handling a variety of graphic-based tasks as well.

## **SKILLS**

## FRONT END DEVELOPER

Vanilla Javascript | React.JS | NEXT.JS | Vue.js | NUXT.js | jQuery | SCSS | Bootstrap | WordPress

- Convert Figma and PSD designs into fully functional websites and applications using React.js, NEXT.js, Redux, Vanilla Javascript and Ajax.
- Experience with API integration.
- User experience and responsive designs using CSS, SCSS, Media Query and Bootstrap.
- Convert PSD and Figma to responsive WordPress websites.
- Designed E-Commerce websites through WooCommerce Plugin.
- Debug and refactor existing applications and software modules as required.
- Implemented Cross Browser compatibility in websites and applications.
- Animate SVG using SVG animation tags and CSS.
- Add SEO optimization using semantic elements.
- Implement web optimization using google lighthouse.
- Use e3c coding standards.

## BACK END DEVELOPER

NODE | Express | PHP

- Manage user forms and feedback system.
- Experience in RESTful API design and development.
- Develop applications to analyze and manage marketing activities.
- WordPress theme and plugin customization.
- Work with MongoDB and SQL using NODE and core PHP.

### WEB DEPLOYMENT

GitHub | Vercel | Netlify | NameCheap | CPanel

- Manage domains, sub-domains, databases, emails, and media on CPanel.
- Integration CPanel with Netlify.
- Manage clients' NameCheap accounts including domain, hosting and email hosting.
- Use GitHub for version control.
- Deploy or migrate WordPress applications with database integration.
- Deploy PHP applications and websites with SQL integration.
- Manage MongoDB on MongoDB Atlas.

# **EDUCATION**

## University

University Of Karachi (UBIT) Bachelors Of Computer Science 2017-2020

## **High School**

D.J. Sindh Government Science College Pre-Engineering 2013 – 2015

## Matriculation

The Educators Science 2003 – 2013

## **COURSE**

## Web Development

Computer Collegiate January 2019 - June 2019

# **AWARDS**

## **Certificate To Appreciate**

Bizz World Communications July 2020 - September 2020

### HTTP://MOHAMMADAHMERMALICK.COM



# SKILLS I CONTINUED

#### **MARKETING**

SendGrid | Email Template | APIs

- Develop an application to automate mass email through Sendgrid API.
- Create dynamic and responsive email templates.
- Redirecting email from domain to domain.
- Manage email assets and keep records.

#### **GRAPHIC**

Figma | Photoshop | Illustrator | Sony Vegas | Blender

- Slice UI elements.
- Vectorize logo.
- Export web optimized images.
- Create and optimize SVGs for animation.
- · Photo Blending.
- Color Correction.
- Background Removing.
- Video editing on Sony Vegas.
- 3D Modeling / Texturing / Material.
- 3D Animation / Simulation.

# SKILLS SUMMARY

- Design pixel perfect websites and applications using the latest technologies.
- Design SAAP applications on the latest technologies like Next.js, Nest.js and tailwind.
- Can carry out backend and database jobs.
- Proficient in all major graphic software including Figma, Photoshop and Illustrator.
- Have experience in deployment and hosting platforms.
- Efficiently drive web and graphic teams and supervise with management software including Asana, Slack and Github.
- Collaborate with the team and international clients to produce a variety of concepts.

HTML CSS SCSS BOOTSTRAP TAILWIND SVG ANIMATION WORDPRESS

JAVASCRIPT REACT.JS NEXT.JS VUE.JS NUST.JS NODE.JS JQUERY PHP

EMAIL TEMPLATES SENDGRID GITHUB MYSQL MONGODB CPANEL

FIGMA PHOTOSHOP ILLUSTRATOR BLENDER FILMORA SONY VEGAS

MS WORD MS EXCEL MS POWERPOINT